# Michael Saleem

# Network Security Architect

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Palo Alto Networks

PCNSE

PCNSA

F5 Networks

F5 CTS, DNS

F5-CTS, LTM

F5-CA

Cisco

CCNA Security

CCNA R&S

CompTIA

Network +

A +

ITIL

ITIL Foundation

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Networking

Troubleshooting

Firewalls

Load Balancers

TLS / SSL

VPN

DNS

CDN

Proxies

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a committed, reliable, highly focussed and self-driven individual with over 10 years of experience working in I.T.

My skills predominantly revolve around network firewall and load balancer deployment, configuration and troubleshooting. I also have experience with utilising version control systems such as Git / GitHub and automation using REST API calls (via cURL and Postman), F5 DO & AS3.

## PROJECTS / ACHIEVEMENTS

• F5 Subject Matter Expert (SME) – I became a lead escalation point for any F5 load balancer queries and issues. I was also responsible for testing new releases of software code released by the vendor before it was rolled out to our entire fleet of BIG-IP hardware devices across EMEA and APAC regions (over 2000+ devices). In addition to this, I also was awarded 'F5 MVP' for 2024 by the vendor, recognising my expertise and contributions to the technical community <a href="https://community.f5.com/kb/devcentralnews/2024-devcentral-mvp-announcement/326017">https://community.f5.com/kb/devcentralnews/2024-devcentral-mvp-announcement/326017</a>

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Palo Alto Firewalls Next Generation Firewall
  - o App-ID
  - o User-ID
  - Content-ID (Anti-Virus, Anti-Spyware, URL Filtering etc)
  - o GlobalProtect SSL VPN / Site-to-Site VPN
  - o SSL Forward Proxy / Inbound Inspection
- F5 BIG-IP Load Balancer
  - O LTM / GTM / AFM / APM / AVR
- Cisco Firepower Next Generation Firewall
  - o Firepower Device Manager
  - o Firepower Management Centre
  - Cisco Defence Orchestrator
  - o NGFW Policies (e.g. Identity, File and Intrusion Policies)
- Cisco ASA Firewall
  - o Interface, ACL and NAT configuration
  - Site-to-Site VPN configuration (policy based and BGP route-based)
  - o Remote Access VPN configuration (Cisco AnyConnect SSL VPN)
- Citrix ADC (NetScaler) Load Balancer
  - o Configuring servers, service groups and vServers
  - o Configuring responder/rewrite/content switching policies
- Brocade ADX Load Balancer
  - o Configuring servers and virtuals
  - o Configuring CSW rules and policies

#### **EDUCATION**

Ealing Green College

AS Levels: Economics (A) ICT (A) Mathematics (B)

## CONTACT

Michael Saleem Aylesbury Buckinghamshire

E: jobs@michaelsaleem.me

CV Website:

https://www.michaelsaleem.me

Blog:

https://www.michaelsaleem.co.uk

LinkedIn:

<u>linkedin.com/in/michaelsaleem</u>

### REFERENCES

Available on Request

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Rackspace Technology June 2018 - Present

Network Security Architect / Engineer L3

Working on non-BAU work including fleet management, code testing, policies and standards, billable projects (i.e. complex work that falls ouside the normal realm of support).

I am also an escalation point for complex tickets and an F5 subject matter expert within the organisation

# Rackspace Technology A

Aug. 2015 – May. 2017

Network Security Engineer

Rackspace "Fanatic of the Month" Nominee - May 2016

Provided "Fanatical Support" by utilising my skills and knowledge to deliver the most optimal business outcomes to customers while maintaining confidentiality, integrity and availability of their network data.

Ensure SLAs and OLAs are adhered to with quick response and effective action in order to maintain and maximise solution uptime.

#### Duties:

- Install, configure, and troubleshoot NGFW Palo Alto and Cisco Firepower
- Configure and troubleshoot routing, switching DNS, VLANs,
- Install, configure and troubleshoot Cisco ASA and Juniper SRX firewalls
- Install, configure and troubleshoot F5 BIG-IP and Brocade ADX load balancers
- Create and troubleshoot Client-to-Site (IPSEC / SSL) and Site-to-Site VPNs
- Troubleshoot all layers of the OSI model
- Collaborate with fellow engineers and for support and professional development
- Investigate and resolve incident tickets
- Provide Fanatical Support® in all interactions
- Deliver informal training ("brownbag" sessions) to members across multiple teams covering LTM/GTM/AFM configuration and troubleshooting

# Rackspace Technology

Nov. 2014 – Jul. 2015

**Enterprise Support Specialist** 

Primarily responsible for responding to and solving 'quick fix' tickets. The first point of contact for customers calling in with queries and escalating to support teams where necessary. Perform ticket queue management and ensure support SLA are being met.

# Rackspace Technology

Jun. 2013 - Nov. 2014

Data Centre Operations Technician Level 2

- Building, configuring, deploying and troubleshooting with exposure to a vast array of server and network equipment (Dell PowerEdge, HP G1/G2, Cisco Catalyst, Nexus, ASA, Arista, BigIP F5, Brocade ADX, EMC VNX, NetApp)
- Primarily responsible for training new members of my team and mentoring colleagues on ticket update best practices and etiquette